WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
It's called the Arii Poerava,
also known as the Black Pearl.
This pearl ended
the French-Tahitian War in 1847.
It is considered priceless.
They're expecting you at Quai Branly.
Central Precinct will contact you
if there are any security breaches.
- Do you have your phone?
- Affirmative.
- Hello.
- Michael, listen carefully.
If you're already in the car,
respond by saying that it's nice outside.
- Who is this?
- This is Central Precinct.
If you've already gotten in the car,
say it's nice out.
- It's nice out.
- Perfect. Michael, it's not safe.
We have reason to believe that your driver
is working for a criminal organization.
Emergency protocol is in effect.
You know the drill.
Get dropped off at Trocadéro Plaza.
Take the metro.
It's safer for you and the pearl.
Take the south train
to the end of the line.
- Our agents will meet you there.
- Okay.
Change of plans.
Drop me off here, please.
No, no. There's no way!
No!
Come back!
Stop him! Thief! He has the pearl!
Hey. Hey, you.
Hey, you.
Hey, how you doin'? I'm home.
Good boy.
A year after his incredible stunt
at the Pellegrini gala,
France's most famous burglar
has yet to be caught.
While police claim to have several leads,
no arrests have been made.
Experts say his vanishing act would not be
possible without help from accomplices,
or possibly...
You're my accomplice.
While current leads
have yielded no results,
Assane Diop's former wife
is considered a suspect,
though she claims ignorance.
She is being closely watched
by the police and the media as well.
Leave us alone!
Please, leave us alone!
I don't know where he is!
Why don't you get that?!
Leave us alone!
All right, J'accuse.
Time to go home.
- Good night.
UNKNOWN NUMBER
ORANGE UMBRELLA. IN 2 MINUTES.
Claire?
Claire, hold on. Please, Claire, wait!
- Let go of me, Assane!
- I...
I know you're angry.
- I know how you and Raoul feel.
- Oh yeah? You know?
You know what?
You know the fear? Shame?
You know how people stare at us,
how Raoul wakes up screaming at night?
- I swear to...
- No!
Don't say it because you're not sorry
about what you did.
Just shut up, Assane. I'm done.
We can leave, Claire.
Raoul, you, and me.
Let's leave France,
go somewhere where nobody knows us.
I bought tickets
on a cargo ship leaving in 48 hours.
You know what I just realized?
You're insane. Completely insane.
You think Raoul
and I would leave everything for you?
We can be together.
Be a family.
We wouldn't be a family.
We'd be on the run!
Is that the life you want for your kid,
always having to look over his shoulder?
- You really want to fix things?
- I'd do anything for that.
Okay.
Then turn yourself in.
It's the only solution.
That's what I thought.
You're not a hero, Assane.
You're scared.
What did you expect? For her to follow you
and just drop everything?
No, but I was hoping
she'd be glad to talk.
Assane!
You just... Do you realize
what her life has been like this year?
She's always getting questioned
and harassed!
- It's a living hell.
- I know.
Look! She's on every front page this week.
HIS WIFE BRAINWASHED?
I know, Ben.
Okay.
What now?
I have a plan, Ben.
But it's risky.
- Tricky. Dangerous.
- How bad on a scale from one to ten?
Probably a 12.
It's a big job, Ben.
The job.
Of course.
- It all starts with this.
- The Black Pearl.
Stop right there!
Police!
Out of the way!
Stop him!
Come on!
Hey!
- Don't move!
- Hold on, guys! Stop, I'm a cop!
I'm a cop!
Nice try, but this is my badge.
Let's bring him in.
My one failure.
You know I gotta fix my mistake.
Don't make the same mistake twice.
If I have to disappear,
gotta do it with a bang.
You bastard!
WANTED: ASSANE DIOP
Hero or criminal?
France is still making up its mind
about Assane Diop.
According to various sources, he's been
spotted all over France in various...
I can't believe
how insane people are over this guy!
We've had this crook on our front page
for months and nobody knows where he is.
There's... there's nothing left to say.
It's, it's...
This whole thing is insane.
It's a mystery.
It isn't insane.
And readers love a mystery.
Franck, she's just trying to make herself
look good here. It's pretty obvious.
It's obvious it's been three months
since you've been on the front page,
so you're jealous.
You know what I see here?
Two journalists in competition.
That sounds good to me.
But you know the rule. You don't like
the headline? Find a better one.
- Thanks.
- Have a nice day.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Your helmet, please.
- I just have this letter.
- Please remove your helmet.
Here.
Are you okay, ma'am?
You...
You look like that man.
Oh, that guy?
Tell me about it!
He's ruining my damn life.
This happens every day!
Now you too? I'm over it!
Luckily, I'm more handsome.
And, of course,
my eyes are a different color.
What color are my eyes?
- Brown.
- Exactly.
These bad boys are saving me.
Otherwise, I'd be arrested by now.
- Can I get a signature?
- Yes, sir, of course.
It makes sense you're nervous.
This seems like a place he'd want to rob.
Assane Dop.
No, um... Diop.
Diop. Not... not Dop.
Assane Diop. That's right.
I remember now. I'm Michel Beaumont.
And you?
Elizabeth.
Have a good one, Elizabeth.
- Goodbye.
- Thank you, gentlemen.
- My pleasure, ma'am.
Mr. and Mrs. Branville.
So lovely to see you again.
- How are you?
- Very good, thank you.
- Very well.
- Wonderful.
Usually we come down this way.
We can check over there.
Of course, madam. Um...
You can count on us. It's no problem.
I'll see you soon. See you soon. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Mr. Imbert, this is for you.
Thank you. Oh, excuse me.
Hold on for a moment.
I have something for you.
Oh my goodness!
Hello, Captain.
- Commander Félix, from SWAT.
- Commander.
Our men are reinforcing
the security system.
Aren't we waiting
for confirmation it's real?
No, Captain.
A threat is like a live grenade.
We have to defuse it before it blows up.
Major, deploy your men.
We need to get this area secure now.
Of course, Commander.
"Dear Mr. Imbert,
I hope this letter finds you well
and that your hair stylist did a good job
during your coloring session on Monday."
"Being robbed is an unpleasant experience
and I find it's best
for one to be prepared for that."
"I assume your heart,
like your hair, is fragile."
"I thought it best to spare you the shock
and give you an advanced warning
that I plan to steal your Black Pearl."
"I will steal it at 10 p.m. sharp
on the evening of Friday, December 3rd."
"P.S. Allow me to express my sympathies
for any disturbances I may cause."
"Yours respectfully, Assane Diop."
- You're sure that he wrote that?
- He handed it personally to Mrs. Simon.
- You saw him?
- Yes.
But how can you be sure it was Diop?
He's usually in disguise.
Yes, of course.
Of course, it was very subtle.
He... he put in some contacts
to change his eye color. They were brown.
Brown? His eyes are brown.
He...
He said his name was... Michel Beaumont.
Right. We have to keep this a secret.
No one can know Diop has returned.
- Understood?
- Understood.
- Can we see your surveillance footage?
- Uh, yes. It's, uh...
- Can you switch cameras?
- Of course.
There!
He's got one hell of a nerve.
He disappears for a year,
then just walks back in.
He's screwing with us.
What kind of thief
would invite you to his robbery?
Pass the ball!
Block, block!
Go, go, go!
- Coach, call foul!
- What?
That was a foul.
- Whoa, whoa!
- Stop being such a baby, Diop.
It was a foul play. Free throw.
- Can't shoot for shit.
- Hey!
- Diop, you suck. You're gonna miss!
- You suck!
Come on, pussy, relax.
I'm sure your dad's up there watching you.
Knock it off!
Oh, no, my bad. He doesn't give a shit.
Hey, hey, hey!
Knock it off!
- So stupid.
- It's always the same with you!
- Not our fault.
- I'm not here to babysit you!
You're too old for this!
Benjamin!
Hey, Assane.
What's up for your vacation?
Benjamin! Come on!
Paul invited me to his country house.
You're going? You hate Paul.
Our parents are friends.
I don't have a choice.
Okay, well...
Have fun, then.
Assane...
Hold on!
Hey!
Oh, excuse me. Assane!
You lived in Montreuil, right?
On Resistance Avenue?
Yeah, with my father. Why?
I got a call from the new tenant.
They've got your mail.
- They want you to get it.
- It's probably just junk mail.
- They can throw it away.
- He said there were letters from Senegal.
- From Senegal?
- Yes, letters from your family.
Hmm, something like that.
Thanks. Thanks so much.
Okay, that's enough!
Practice is over!
- Seriously?
- Really?
Everyone you know abandons you.
Hey! Meet me outside.
Let me guess. Diop has returned.
Got it.
- Tell me everything.
- Hold on.
- Just tell me.
- This isn't your case anymore.
Don't do this.
You know it's not just any case for me.
That's why you're here, right?
So, tell me. Where is he?
What's he done? Spill it!
He dropped this off with a jeweler
on Place Vendôme.
And he did it in person.
"Dear Mr. Imbert,
I hope this letter finds you well
and your hair stylist did a good job..."
"Being robbed is an unpleasant experience
and I find it's best..."
Same guy, still top of his game.
You find something?
Let me explain.
Lupin often sends his victims a warning
before robbing them.
Grab the letter.
Look here, at the end of his letter.
"Allow me to express my sympathies
for any disturbances I may cause."
"Please accept my humble apologies.
Yours respectfully, Arsène Lupin."
By announcing the theft,
we're forced to show our hand,
which makes the pearl even more...
Vulnerable.
Yeah.
Was the only thing he left behind
the letter?
Uh, no.
He gave a fake name. Beaumont.
- Michel Beaumont?
- Yeah. How'd you know?
In The Crystal Stopper, that's his alias.
Why is he always making
these references to Lupin?
Because he's playing with us.
That's the way he's always done things.
Always one step ahead of us.
- Who else knows about the letter?
- No one.
Take a look at this!
That's what we call a real scoop.
Pay attention.
Fleur here is a real journalist.
Watch and learn.
Margaux, this letter goes
on the front page tomorrow.
I don't know how you did it,
but very well done.
- Keep going.
- Thank you.
Bravo, Fleur!
Whoo!
He's back!
In a letter published this morning
on the front page of The Objector,
the most famous fugitive
in France announced
he is going to steal the Black Pearl,
a priceless gem seized
during the French-Tahitian War in 1846.
Diop states the time
and place of his next hit.
December 3rd at precisely 10 p.m.
at Place Vendôme.
Well, Mr. Diop, if you're watching this,
it's very kind of you to give France
fair warning before your next job.
- We'll be there.
- Oh God. Just great.
It'll be chaos.
Sylvain, I want maps
and access points to all buildings,
and video footage from Place Vendôme.
Close down the whole area!
Max, call the SWAT commander.
We're on maximum alert.
You got it.
If Diop shows up, we'll be ready.
I've heard that one before.
We have 43 cameras here on site.
Another one here.
Motion sensors in every room.
How many exits?
Six, counting
the service stairwell.
- Any codes?
- A four-digit code.
- Same one for every door.
- You should change it now.
We change it weekly.
Have you changed it
since you got the letter?
I'll change it right now.
It's possible, Mr. Imbert,
that Assane Diop has already been here.
Maybe he's watching now.
The threat is real, Mr. Imbert.
Don't take this letter lightly.
This is really high up.
- We're on the second floor.
- Yeah, a fear of heights is terrible.
All right.
The further you go
to the center of the room,
the more valuable
the items on display are.
That's the reason why the Black Pearl
is right here, in the center.
It's worth more
than all our jewels combined.
The pearl should be
behind bulletproof glass.
We're better than that. Look.
ACTIVATE MAIN GALLERY
ALARM ACTIVATED
If you touch one of these beams...
ALARM DEACTIVATED
Good, that's perfect.
I'll have my men covering the room.
- Oh? How many men?
- Just enough, Mr. Imbert.
I can assure you
no one will lay a finger on your pearl.
The nation's honor is at stake.
What?
You remind me of your mom.
If he's coming tonight, we won't miss him.
I have to show you something.
I'll be back.
- You have the code?
- Imbert gave it to me.
- What the hell's going on?
- They're all here for Diop.
Fucking Robin Hood.
Robin Hood gave
what he stole to the poor.
Diop gets revenge for them.
No, no, not this time. No.
Major, I need you and your men to move in.
- Let's go!
- Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
Go!
Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
I never thought I'd ask you this,
but should I read the original books?
What are you talking about?
What books?
The books. Arsène Lupin.
"Lubar"?
Never heard of it.
Guédira, I'm serious.
Don't make me beg!
Took you long enough. Let me explain.
If you wanna catch him,
you need to know Lupin.
- What do you need to know?
- You tell me.
I'm trying to anticipate his next move.
No, you don't get it,
you can't do that.
- The guy's a con artist.
- You're not helping.
I need you to think
and tell me how he'd pull it off.
No idea. He'll probably try
to distract you.
in place? Impossible!
He's a gentleman thief.
He always finds a way.
Unless he's stolen it already.
- Are you serious?
- That would be a very Lupin thing to do.
Is this the original?
Of course it is. Why even ask?
No one could've exchanged it
without you knowing?
On my watch? Impossible.
He hasn't stolen it.
In 2017,
some guy tried to steal it.
We got the pearl back,
but the guy got away.
Guy's description sounded like Diop.
And if it was him,
that means it's his only failure.
Okay,
SWAT will inspect everything closely.
Yeah.
Hundreds have come
in the hope of catching a glimpse
of the most wanted fugitive
currently being searched for in France.
If he pulls this off tonight,
as he announced on social media,
we could be standing
in front of what could be
the most daring burglary in history.
Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
Who the hell are you?
Diop. Assane Diop.
I used to live here.
Thank you.
"Tell Sanni Mom loves him,
but he's better off without me."
Mama.
Give me all your money!
Bro, what's
with the dorky clothes?
- Bruno!
- Oh, sorry, did I freak you out?
When did you become such a wimp?
- You good?
- Yeah.
Come on, we'll miss the match.
France is doing great.
There's no way we'll lose.
He passes to Thierry once again.
He's dribbling down the field,
going in for the goal.
He goes and shoots,
and he is blocked!
They've got the ball
and they're traveling toward the goal.
All of France is watching
for the outcome of this game.
Thierry has been
the star player this time,
getting all of the goals for this game.
He's gotten two goals
and he's on a hat-trick.
- Thierry has recaptured the ball.
- Oh!
Thierry's got it, heading in
on the goal, lines up, he shoots!
Goal!
- Yeah!
- This wins the game!
- Amazing! Thierry again...
Thank you, Thierry!
Thank you!
...going to the finals
of the World Cup!
- Hey!
- Yeah?
Can I stay with you? For a few days.
...victory for France.
The crowd is going wild.
Of course, man.
You can feel the excitement
for the people of our country.
- Captain Belkacem, everything is in order.
- Get the shutters and alarm.
The alarm is activated.
Mr. Imbert, come on.
Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
ASSANE MAKES THE 1% PAY
- If he ran, I'd vote for him.
- You want a thief for President?
He's not the thief, the others are!
All these cops for one man?
They'll never catch him!
What is it
that draws you to Assane Diop?
He's the voice of the people!
That's my man!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
WHO'S NEXT?
Assane Diop! Assane Diop! Assane...
All right, thanks.
All good downstairs.
Ten! Nine!
Eight! Seven!
Six!
Five!
Four!
Three!
Two!
One!
Zero!
DIOP: PLACE VENDÔME BURGLARY
Whoo!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Open the door! The code!
On our way.
Come on, hurry!
Go, go, go, go!
Where is it? Come on, move, move!
The hallways, the hallways! Go!
What the hell happened?
Where's the pearl?
Hello!
This is impossible! Take off your mask!
Shit! He has to be nearby.
You, take off your mask!
What...
But...
Look.
There! But...
Check the exits!
The upper floors too!
What is it?
Some officer is making his way
to my office using all the building codes!
- What? Are you serious?
- I can see him right now.
Vidal! Diop is upstairs! Now!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
- There, there!
- Go, go, go!
Come on, hurry up!
Would you hurry up?
Let me do it, idiot!
Open the door now!
Mr. Imbert, you changed
the code earlier. Hurry up!
- What are you waiting for?
- I'm not a mechanic!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop! Assane...
Diop!
All units to the courtyard! Now!
You, don't move!
Don't move! Stop resisting!
I said don't move!
Spread your legs! Stop resisting!
- Give me your hand!
- We're taking you in!
Give me your hand!
Let's go.
All units,
we're exiting through the front.
- The Black Pearl...
- My one failure.
Let him go!
Free Assane Diop! Let him go!
Free Assane Diop!
Let him go! Free Assane Diop!
Here he is!
Free Assane Diop!
Let him go! Free Assane Diop! Let him go!
Free Assane Diop! Let him go!
Free Assane Diop!
Let him go! Free Assane Diop!
Let him go!
Free Assane Diop!
Let him go! Free Assane Diop!
And now, coming up,
we've got a discussion
about a person of great interest...
3 DAYS EARLIER
Bruno here?
- Can I come in?
- Bold of you to come here.
I don't know what you're doing
and I don't care. Come in.
Thanks.
Take a seat. He won't be long.
Hero or criminal?
France is still making up its mind
about Assane Diop.
According to various sources,
he's been spotted all over France,
in various locations.
The police are doing everything they can
to check out every possible lead,
even ones that may seem suspicious.
Looking to the overseas territories,
police haven't ruled out the possibility
that he could have escaped
out of the country.
Unfortunately,
this does broaden the search.
However, many experts believe
Assane is still in France,
his work as a thief not finished.
Hey, Bruno.
I'm here to pay my debt.
Got an offer for you.
So here's the plan.
Meet me tomorrow at dawn.
At Place Vendôme.
You remember Benjamin Férel?
- Hey, Bruno.
- Hey.
Go on.
Inside the pillar
is the perfect hiding spot.
Look.
Earpiece.
Here. For you.
Stay in contact, okay?
Your outfit.
You're gonna pose
as a recently transferred SWAT commander.
- Hello. Commander Félix from SWAT.
- Commander.
Take control of the operation.
Our men are reinforcing
the security system.
Aren't we waiting for confirmation
it's real?
No, Captain.
A threat is like a live grenade.
Act natural.
They won't question anything.
Major, deploy your men.
We need to get this area secure now.
Of course.
The bigger the lie,
the more they buy it.
I want to know everything
about their security systems.
You'll be my eyes and ears.
- Ready, Commander?
- Uh-huh.
Adjust your badge if you read me.
Very good. Get in there.
Ask to see the manager, Mr. Imbert.
We have 43 cameras here on site.
Another one here.
Motion sensors in every room.
How many exits?
Six, counting
the service stairwell.
- Ask him for the codes.
- Any codes?
A four-digit code,
same one for every door.
- Change it right now.
- You should change it now.
I'll change it right now.
Say that maybe I was already there.
It's possible
that Assane Diop has already been here.
Or maybe he's watching now.
The threat is real, Mr. Imbert.
Don't take this letter lightly.
Okay, turn around.
Shit.
Oh, this is high up.
This is really high up.
We're on the second floor.
Is he stupid?
Yeah, a fear of heights is terrible.
CODE ALTERED
The Black Pearl is right here.
In the center.
It's worth more
than all our jewels combined.
They have lasers protecting the pearl,
but that's not something you know.
Tell him to put it
behind bulletproof glass.
The pearl should be
We're better than that. Look.
The more interest you show
in his pearl, the more he'll trust you.
Tell him that this job
protecting the pearl is personal for you.
Actually, wait.
Tell him the honor of France is at stake.
I told you. The bigger the lie, man...
Well, good. That's perfect.
I'll have my men covering the room.
- Oh, how many men?
- Just enough, Mr. Imbert.
I can assure you
no one will lay a finger on your pearl.
The nation's honor is at stake.
Explain to me why I had to send
a copy of the letter to The Objector.
We gotta fill the square with people.
What's the best way to announce
your party? Send invitations.
Take a look at this.
That's what we call a real scoop!
I don't know how you did it,
but very well done. Keep going.
Thank you.
Don't forget the news.
There's a lot of viewers.
Mr. Diop, if you're watching this,
it's very kind of you
to give France fair warning
before your next job.
We'll be there.
Assane Diop!
There's perks
to being a wanted man.
- I need you and your men to move in.
- Let's go!
Assane Diop! Assane Diop!
Act One. We use the crowd
to infiltrate the SWAT unit.
Neither seen nor heard.
Let's go, let's go! Come on!
Ten!
Nine! Eight!
Seven!
Six! Five!
Four!
Three!
Two!
One!
Zero!
What the hell happened?
Where's the pearl?
I don't know. It's just gone.
This is impossible. Take off your mask!
Shit! He has to be nearby.
Act Two. We make our escape.
With the right code,
you can open any door.
And if you want
to avoid unexpected visitors...
...you just change the code.
- What are you waiting for?
- I'm not a mechanic!
If I say it's not working,
it's not working!
I'll be at the rendezvous point
in two minutes.
Mr. Imbert, you changed
the code earlier. Hurry up!
And finally, Act Three...
You, don't move, don't move!
Stop resisting!
I said don't move! Spread your legs!
- Stop resisting!
- Give me your hand!
We go out with a bang.
- Let's go.
- We'll go out the front door.
Liberté pour Assane Diop! Liberté...
The crowd that helped us get in
will keep the police busy.
They'll see us, but won't really look.
You get it.
We take our final bows.
And then, the curtain drops.
Assane Diop!
We love you!
You're a mad man, Assane.
- I cannot believe we made it!
- Amazing job, guys.
Now that I paid you,
you think your sister will stop hating me?
We'll be happy
to never see you again.
This is your stop.
Meet me at the spot.
Person spotted on rooftops
near Place Vendôme.
Wait, it's Assane Diop!
We don't have the location
of his transport. Confirm identity.
I lost him. He's on the run.
We're sending backup.
Someone fell off the roof!